<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Cosmos Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Internet of Blockchains]]></description><link>http://cosmos.network</link><image><url>http://cosmos.network/static/favicon.png</url><title>Cosmos Blog</title><link>http://cosmos.network</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 15:22:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cosmos.network/static//rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 15:22:12 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[2016 Cosmos Foundation]]></copyright><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><managingEditor><![CDATA[Cosmos Foundation]]></managingEditor><webMaster><![CDATA[Cosmos Foundation]]></webMaster><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Think Like a Hacker. Make it Big]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Ladies and gentlemen, a small appeal to the most scrutinizing eyeballs of our industry.</p>
<p>Cosmos hasn’t been called ‘tinder for blockchains’ for no reasons. Connecting different blockchains is at the core of our mission. When it come to choosing how to conduct our fundraiser, we naturally chose to accept both BTC and ETH.</p>
<p>Keeping the fundraiser safe for all parties is critical and dealing with both tokens adds additional surface area for attacks and potential issues. That is why are extending, as of today, ample rewards for anyone with both the time and skills to really dig into our flows.</p>
<p>Put plainly, we are offering:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>15 BTC</em> for major, show-stopping bugs found in our fundraiser flow.</li>
<li>Up to <em>5 BTC</em> for minor bugs that won’t kill the fundraiser, but which will be an embarrassment or an inconvenience for either Cosmos or its funders.</li>
<li>You can also claim your reward in Atoms.</li>
</ul>
<p>The materials in question can be found here:</p>
<ul>
<li>BTC: <a href="https://gist.github.com/mappum/428dc46afba73b2bf8c38f65272704d2">https://gist.github.com/mappum/428dc46afba73b2bf8c38f65272704d2</a></li>
<li>ETH: <a href="https://github.com/ethcore/contracts/blob/e340700342733b26acbe6949118986b60f2d274e/Receipter.sol#L90">https://github.com/ethcore/contracts/blob/e340700342733b26acbe6949118986b60f2d274e/Receipter.sol#L90</a></li>
</ul>
<p>These repositories include both the Web-based fundraiser for Bitcoin, and the Solidity contracts for Ethereum. Both are relevant to this bounty. So this is your chance to put your hacker cap on, think like a deviant and strike it big in the crypto space.</p>
<p>In the interest of being thorough, our friends at Zeppelin (Smart Contract Solutions) are simultaneously performing an audit for these same materials. Don’t worry, if you independently discover a bug that they also find but haven’t published yet, you may still claim the reward.</p>
<p>Last but not least, we want to express our thanks to participants in the Cosmos Whitepaper Bounty, particularly GitHub user MartyMe, who took the 5 BTC bounty with his excellent contributions to both the DEX and the Hub Block Reward.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, this show is nearly on the road, just a few more miles to go. We look forward to a successful fundraiser, and to building the Internet of Blockchains with you!</p>
]]></description><link>http://cosmos.network/posts/fundraiser-flow-bounty</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://cosmos.network/posts/fundraiser-flow-bounty</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Cosmonauts]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cosmos Whitepaper Bounty]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Out here in Cosmos land, we have been hard at work getting everything prepared
for the big fundraiser. We could not be more pleased to see that the vision for
the Internet of Blockchains has been slowly catching on in the community,  with
our research and preparation solidifying nicely as well.</p>
<p>Pertaining to the fundraiser, we have a sequence of announcements to make in
the coming weeks. We would love both your feedback and your assistance to
ensure that we make the fundraiser a success. Ultimately, the goal of
connecting the disparate blockchains and enabling moving money seamlessly
between them is substantial, with a number of moving parts, each of some
complexity… Your questions and comments help us to hone our communications,
hopefully  leading to simpler, clearer explanations of all aspects of this
Cosmos that we will build together.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://cosmos.network/blog/cosmos-roadmap">our last post</a>, we wrote about the different components of the Cosmos Network
and our strategic roadmap. This week we are soliciting your input and
announcing the first of two bounties!</p>
<h2>Whitepaper Bounty</h2>
<p>The Cosmos whitepaper was published last summer, and we received excellent
questions, comments, and general feedback about it. But this was rather
informal, and we did not in any way officially onboard the feedback we
received. Today that changes: Before we launch the fundraiser, we want to
invite a public review of the whitepaper, really an open line to question our
premises and our proposed solutions. We know that many of you will have
brilliant ideas that we haven’t yet heard, and we want to be certain that the
Cosmos system is not only technically and conceptually bulletproof, but
absolutely imbued with the best ideas, from the best minds!</p>
<p>So of course, we are especially interested in exploring the overall Cosmos
architecture; those technical or economic flaws that we might have overlooked.
But fear not, the long hours you’ll spend wearing your well-trodden thinking
cap, brooding over our oh-so-cosmic ideas shall not go unrewarded. For usable
contributions, we will give out in aggregate 5 bitcoins. We might award that
entirely to the best and most shattering contribution, or we may perhaps split
it out over several different ones. In addition, depending on how your review
affects your belief in the project, you may choose to receive your reward in
either bitcoin or in atoms!</p>
<p>Here are the rules and process:</p>
<ol>
<li>Though any platform for discussion may be initially used, all
contributions must ultimately be filed formally as GitHub issues.</li>
<li><strong>The repository for filing is <a href="https://github.com/cosmos/cosmos/issues">https://github.com/cosmos/cosmos/issues</a> and
you should tag @jaekwon and @ebuchman.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Please make your point as descriptive as it needs to be, but no more.  A
summary of the concern, followed by a more broad description, is probably
ideal.</strong></li>
<li>The review begins today, Wednesday the 15th of February, and will run
until Friday February 24th at midnight PST.</li>
</ol>
<p>As always, if you have any questions or comments, you can find us on
<a href="http://slack.cosmos.network">Slack</a>,
<a href="http://reddit.com/r/thecosmos">Reddit</a>, and/or
<a href="http://twitter.com/cosmos_hq">Twitter</a>. We look forward to your contributions!</p>
<p>The Cosmos Team</p>
]]></description><link>http://cosmos.network/posts/cosmos-whitepaper-bounty</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://cosmos.network/posts/cosmos-whitepaper-bounty</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Cosmonauts]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cosmos Roadmap]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In Cosmos land, we have been hard at work with getting everything ready for the
big fundraiser. The Internet of Blockchain meme has been slowly catching on in
the blockchain community and the vision has solidified in our research and
preparation as well.</p>
<p>We will have a sequence of announcements coming in the next weeks and we would
love your help and feedback to ensure that we make the fundraiser a success and
most importantly realize the ultimate goal of connecting the disparate
blockchains and enabling moving money seamlessly between chains.</p>
<p>In this post, we want to share some information about the components of the
Cosmos network and in what sequence we want to release and prioritize those
components.</p>
<h1>Two Funding Milestones</h1>
<p>We are dividing the different components of the Cosmos Network into two
different parts. The first part is the Cosmos Essential Software and Services.
It contains the minimum components needed to make sure that Cosmos works and is
functional.</p>
<p>While basic functionality is great, there is a lot to do that goes beyond that
to realize the full vision of Cosmos. Once the basic components have been
built, we will have another set of projects and components to build to enhance
the usefulness, usability and connectivity of the network.</p>
<h2>Cosmos Essential Software and Services (CESS)</h2>
<p>CESS consists of all the software necessary to deploy a minimal network that is
deserving of the phrase “Internet of Blockchains”. At its heart lies the Cosmos
Hub, a complete, multi-asset, proof-of-stake blockchain with built-in
governance and support for the <a href="https://github.com/tendermint/basecoin/blob/develop/docs/guide/ibc.md">InterBlockchain Communication (IBC) protocol</a>.
CESS also includes zones that serve as bridges to the public Bitcoin and
Ethereum networks, as well as a <a href="https://github.com/cosmos/cosmos/blob/master/DEX.md">decentralized exchange (the Cosmos DEX)</a> and an
<a href="https://github.com/tendermint/ethermint/">Ethermint</a> zone, which runs the full Ethereum state machine on Tendermint
consensus.</p>
<p>There will be five blockchains that launch with the Cosmos Network: Hub, DEX,
Bitcoin-Bridge, Ethereum-Bridge, and Ethermint.</p>
<p>The Cosmos Hub itself is built using two key pieces: <a href="https://github.com/tendermint/tendermint">Tendermint</a> and <a href="https://github.com/tendermint/basecoin">Basecoin</a>.
Tendermint is the general purpose consensus engine that will be used, at least
initially, for all blockchains in Cosmos; it is nearing a production-ready
state, and is <a href="https://tendermint.com/ecosystem">already in use by many different organizations</a>. Basecoin is an
<a href="https://cosmos.network/blog/cosmos-creating-interoperable-blockchains-part-1">extendable framework</a>
for building multi-asset cryptocurrency applications on
Tendermint. It’s under active development and includes many working <a href="https://github.com/tendermint/basecoin-examples">example
plugins</a>.
To build the Hub, we need Basecoin plugins for IBC that will manage
validators and their stake, manage delegators and their stake, slash validators
that misbehave, and manage governance. These are in various states of
development.</p>
<p>The Bitcoin and Ethereum bridges will enable Cosmos to interoperate with the
public Bitcoin and Ethereum networks through the mechanism of two-way pegs,
familiar to many as <a href="https://blockstream.com/technology/">“sidechains”</a>. These will be sidechains of Bitcoin and
Ethereum, which will enable users to move BTC and ETH to and from the Cosmos
Network. Once in the Cosmos Network, they can be transferred through the Hub to
other zones, including the decentralized exchange. ETH can also be transferred
to Ethermint zones, where it can be used to power applications written for the
EVM, but running on a faster consensus algorithm such as Tendermint.</p>
<p>Finally, CESS includes wallet software for managing funds, sending transactions
on the Cosmos Network, and participating in governance.</p>
<p>In summary, the foundational components of the project include:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tendermint/tendermint"><strong>Tendermint</strong></a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tendermint/basecoin"><strong>Basecoin Framework</strong></a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tendermint/basecoin"><strong>Hub</strong> (IBC, PoS/Delegation, Governance)</a></li>
<li><strong>Bitcoin and Ethereum bridges</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/cosmos/cosmos/blob/master/DEX.md"><strong>DEX</strong></a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tendermint/ethermint"><strong>Ethermint</strong></a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Auxiliary Software and Services</h2>
<p>The auxiliary software and services includes tools which contribute greatly to
the usability, functionality, and adoption of the Cosmos Network. In
particular, we have identified the following elements:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Blockchain Explorer</strong>: an advanced UI for navigating the Cosmos Network,
including analyzing activity within zones, traffic across zones, the
performance of validators, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Fluidity Smart Contract Framework</strong>: a new programming language
environment for building deterministic and halting programs that can run on a
blockchain. The intent is to take lessons learned from the design of
Ethereum’s Solidity to provide something equally accessible, and with greater
support for extensibility, testing, and safety.</li>
<li><strong>Community Events and Support</strong>: funding for meetups around the world and
particular events, such as in (but not excluded to) San Francisco, Toronto,
New York, Berlin, and Seoul, where many of our developers and community are
based.</li>
<li><strong>Additional Zones</strong>: examples include ZCash, Monero, Bitcoin, and
others. Community opinion will inform which zones we build.</li>
<li><strong>Cosmic Grants</strong>: A program, which awards grants for projects and research
efforts for advancing the internet of blockchain vision.</li>
</ul>
<h1>Development Timeline</h1>
<p>The development timeline for Cosmos is split across five eras: Synthesis,
Atomic Era, Galactic Era, Planetary Era, and Lunar Era.</p>
<h2>Synthesis</h2>
<p>Synthesis is the period in which the Hub is built. It began over two years ago
with the birth of the Tendermint project and continues today with the
development of the Basecoin framework and the various plugins necessary to
compose the Cosmos Hub.</p>
<h2>Atomic Era</h2>
<p>The Atomic Era starts roughly 4 months after the completion of the fundraiser.
It is marked by the release of an Alpha version of the Cosmos Hub and a
corresponding testnet. This includes a working form of the governance,
proof-of-stake, delegation, and IBC modules, as well as a working wallet for
making transactions on the Cosmos Hub. The testnet will include a genesis state
derived from the results of the fundraiser, enabling all who participated to
test the network.</p>
<h2>Galactic Era</h2>
<p>The Galactic Era starts roughly 8 months after the completion of the fundraiser
and is marked by the release of the first production version of the Cosmos Hub
and the first blockchain to be launched in the Cosmos Network. It also marks
the beginning of work on the Bitcoin and Ethereum bridges, as well as the DEX.
These zones will be iterated on as newer versions are connected to the hub.</p>
<h2>Planetary Era</h2>
<p>The Planetary Era starts roughly 12 months after the completion of the
fundraiser and marks the first period of stability for the Cosmos Network,
including working Bitcoin and Ethereum bridges, and a working decentralized
exchange. At this point, the focus will shift to usability and extensive
documentation to in order to help new users and developers integrating with the
Cosmos Network. Further details will be announced based on changing conditions.</p>
<h2>Lunar Era</h2>
<p>It is unclear when the Lunar Era starts, but it is marked by a sublime state of
mind that results from the satisfaction of the Cosmos Network having reached
maturity. Similar to the feeling one would experienced when sipping a cocktail
on a beach and glancing at a coconut tree that has blossomed into its full
beauty after a seed planted years before.</p>
<h1>Conclusion</h1>
<p>Development on the Cosmos Essential Software and Services continues at quite a clip,
and the road ahead is well defined and full of exciting technology.
We’re looking forward to building this out with the community and
making the Internet of Blockchains a reality for everyone!</p>
]]></description><link>http://cosmos.network/posts/cosmos-roadmap</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://cosmos.network/posts/cosmos-roadmap</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Cosmonauts]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fundraiser delay announcement]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Dear backers and long term supporters,</p>
<p>Although February 28th was the most recently cited launch date for our Cosmos
fundraising event, after careful consideration we’ve decided to push this event
back a bit further. For the time being, <em>no new date</em> has been set, but we are
hopeful that we are delayed by less than a single month. Here is why:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>After communicating with many of our most committed funders, we have decided
to accept both Ether (ETH) and Bitcoin (BTC). This is a trickier matter than
it may seem to be on the surface. In order to do it securely, we <em>must</em>
perform audits on our fundraiser code, fixing any issues that we find. At
the moment we don’t know exactly how long this will take. The initial flow
will be finalized by Monday next week (Feb 13th), and promptly delivered to
auditors. Soon after, we’ll make the code available for public review, and
provide bounties for anybody who discovers issues.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We <em>must</em> finalize the Cosmos roadmap. In order to finalize the roadmap, we
are concluding negotiations with interested parties and reviewing financial
details regarding the core Cosmos software. These details should be released
by Thursday (Feb 9th) for public review.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We’ve updated our whitepaper and will be seeking feedback over the coming
days. As with the fundraiser code, we are going to post bounties for the
best feedback/contributions to the whitepaper. This will be announced
formally in short order, but if anyone wants to get a head start, the
current whitepaper is available at
<a href="https://github.com/cosmos/cosmos/blob/master/WHITEPAPER.md">https://github.com/cosmos/cosmos/blob/master/WHITEPAPER.md</a>. Details about
the bounty system will likewise be posted soon at
<a href="https://github.com/cosmos/cosmos/blob/master/BOUNTY.md">https://github.com/cosmos/cosmos/blob/master/BOUNTY.md</a>.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Some time has passed since we first announced that we are doing the fundraiser.
I really appreciate everyone who continues to stick with us while we work all
the details out. The decision to delay was made after careful consideration; we
really want to be absolutely sure everything is going to be as secure as
possible, leading (hopefully) to a very awesome and successful fundraiser.</p>
<p>We will announce the new date for the fundraiser two weeks before it goes live.
You can check the <a href="http://slack.cosmos.network">Cosmos Slack</a> or
<a href="http://cosmos.network">subscribe to our newsletter</a> to get updates.</p>
<p>Thanks again to everyone who has followed and supported our work; this is going
to be a great year!</p>
<p>-Jae and team</p>
]]></description><link>http://cosmos.network/posts/fundraiser-delay-announcement</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://cosmos.network/posts/fundraiser-delay-announcement</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jae Kwon]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cosmos: Creating Interoperable Blockchains — Part 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A series on <a href="http://cosmos.network/">Cosmos</a>, the internet of blockchains powered by the <a href="http://tendermint.com/">Tendermint</a> consensus engine. <em>View blog post on <a href="https://medium.com/@jaekwon/cosmos-creating-interoperable-blockchains-part-1-2929435ba1fa#.kmwc5d4px">Medium</a>.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>There are several ways to create public blockchain applications today. The
primary ones are:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Create your own blockchain from scratch, as Satoshi Nakamoto did.</strong> This
requires one to two years of full-time dedicated programming to get a completed
system, and should not be attempted without a very good reason.</li>
<li><strong>Fork an existing blockchain stack like Bitcoin, as various altcoins such as
<strong><a href="https://github.com/namecoin/namecoin-core">Namecoin</a></strong> have done.</strong> This
works well if the base codebase is well designed to be modular, but that’s
rarely the case.</li>
<li><strong>Write a “smart contract” in an on-chain interpreted language such as
<a href="https://solidity.readthedocs.io/en/develop/">Solidity</a></strong>. This is currently the
best option for creating simple public blockchain applications, but it requires
learning and debugging two levels of complexity — the virtual-machine bytecode
interpreter, and the smart contract language.</li>
</ol>
<p>With <a href="http://tendermint.com/">Tendermint</a> we introduced a fourth way of creating
new public blockchain applications (and by extension, private/consortium apps as
well):</p>
<p><strong>4. Write a state-machine in any language (e.g. Golang, Python, etc), and plug
it into Tendermint’s consensus engine.</strong> Tendermint is responsible for p2p
networking, consensus, and transaction broadcasting. After nodes come to
consensus on a block, they push it to the state-machine via a unix-socket
protocol called <a href="https://github.com/tendermint/abci">ABCI</a> (formerly known as
TMSP).</p>
<p>Tendermint solves a lot of problems for blockchains, but when it comes to
<em>public</em> blockchains, there are additional common concerns that must be
addressed to provide availability. We must balance the desire to provide
permissionless and censorship-resistant access with the need to prevent spam and
denial-of-service (DoS) attacks. While there are many solutions to this problem,
the most common one is to charge a market-rate fee for each transaction. When
there is a surge in demand for a blockchain’s resources, the classical
supply-vs-demand market mechanism can ensure that your transaction will go
through in a timely manner if you pay a sufficiently high fee, and also that
sustained DoS attacks will incur significant costs to the attacker.</p>
<p>Ethereum evolved this concept of transaction fees even further by introducing
the transaction <em>gas</em>, which priced each CPU operation and prevented infinite
for-loops and CPU-heavy smart contracts from hogging the blockchain’s resources.
The user can choose to pay however much they want in <em>fees</em>, and can also set
the <em>gas_limit</em> (i.e. CPU-operations limit) of the transaction. The value of
<em>fees/gas_limit</em> or <em>gas_price</em> is a bid on each CPU-operation. It is the job of
the miner to to pack as many transactions into a block as possible such that
<em>sum(gas_limit) ≤ block_gas_limit</em>, to maximize fee revenue.</p>
<p>Interestingly, Ethereum chooses to refund a proportion of fees when the
transaction does not use all of the gas specified in the <em>gas_limit</em>. This puts
the burden of gas-usage prediction on the miner, which may be suboptimal
compared to taking all of the fees, and letting the user calculate the expected
<em>gas_limit</em> themselves.</p>
<p>Transaction <em>gas</em> is a powerful concept, and can be applied more generally to
blockchain applications that don’t support an interpreted virtual-machine. For
example, the <a href="https://cosmos.network/whitepaper#the-hub">Cosmos Hub</a> can support
inter-blockchain (IBC) token-transfer transactions from any Tendermint-powered
sidechain (aka zone), regardless of the number of validators. (Validators are
nodes that participate in consensus to commit blocks). And yet, the more
validators there are in the zone, the more signatures there will be in the
block-hash commit of an IBC transaction. We can solve this with gas such that
interoperating with blockchains with larger validator-sets costs more. (Of
course we could also solve this with <a href="https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/be29/fa28770bdbbe3d6962d82ab8744658fbfd39.pdf">cryptographic threshold multi-signature
algorithms</a>,
but the same concept applies for IBC transactions that require a long
Merkle-proof).</p>
<p>Taking the lessons on transaction gas that we’ve learned in implementing the
Ethereum virtual-machine (which got integrated into ErisDB), we’ve implemented a
toy cryptocurrency project called
<a href="https://github.com/tendermint/basecoin">Basecoin</a> that will become the basis
for the Cosmos Hub. Basecoin (not to be confused with the excellent service
<a href="http://coinbase.com/">Coinbase</a>) is so named because its goal is to become a
basis layer for Tendermint-based cryptocurrency applications. It is a
multi-asset system at its core, and is intended to accommodate a wide variety of
applications from simple cryptocurrencies to complex systems like Ethereum.</p>
<pre><code>// A Basecoin user account
type Account struct {
  PubKey   crypto.PubKey
  Sequence int
  Balance  Coins
}

type Coin struct {
  Denom  string // e.g. &quot;BTC&quot;, &quot;ATOM&quot;
  Amount int64
}

type Coins []Coin
</code></pre>
<figcaption>Basecoin accounts are natively multi-asset</figcaption>
<p>Basecoin by default provides the ability to send coins from multiple inputs to
multiple outputs with the <em>SendTx</em> transaction. Inputs and outputs are
Ethereum-style accounts (rather than UTXOs), so it’s quite a flexible system.</p>
<p>But what’s more interesting is the secondary kind of transaction, the <em>AppTx</em> transaction. <em>AppTx</em> transactions are processed by a programmer-provided plugin
module. The interface of a Basecoin plugin can be seen below.</p>
<pre><code>type Plugin interface {
    // Name of this plugin, should be short.
    Name() string
  
    // Run a transaction from ABCI DeliverTx
    RunTx(store KVStore, ctx CallContext, txBytes []byte) (res abci.Result)
  
    // Other ABCI message handlers
    SetOption(store KVStore, key string, value string) (log string)
    InitChain(store KVStore, vals []*abci.Validator)
    BeginBlock(store KVStore, height uint64)
    EndBlock(store KVStore, height uint64) []*abci.Validator
}

type CallContext struct {
    CallerAddress []byte   // Caller's Address (hash of PubKey)
    CallerAccount *Account // Caller's Account, w/ fee &amp; TxInputs deducted
    TxInput       Coins    // The coins that the caller wishes to spend, excluding fees
}
</code></pre>
<figcaption>The Basecoin Plugin interface</figcaption>
<p>The important function is the <em>RunTx</em> interface method, which is what you need
to implement in order to extend Basecoin with any functionality you want,
whether it be IBC coin-transfer, or an EVM smart-contract call. Perhaps you’d
like to program an entirely new smart-contract system based on a novel
virtual-machine design. The simplicity of the <em>RunTx</em> interface makes it easy to
get started. Behind the scenes, updates to the <em>KVStore</em> get Merkle-ized and
persisted to disk automatically. And of course you don’t need to worry about
complicated networking and consensus logic because Tendermint takes care of that
for you.</p>
<p>Basecoin is still a work-in-progress, and it’s (back) in active development. If
you feel like hacking Basecoin, check out our <a href="http://slack.cosmos.network/">Slack #basecoin
channel</a> and give us a holler!</p>
]]></description><link>http://cosmos.network/posts/cosmos-creating-interoperable-blockchains-part-1</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://cosmos.network/posts/cosmos-creating-interoperable-blockchains-part-1</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jae Kwon]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why We Are Building the Internet of Blockchains]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>One of the great tragedies of cryptocurrencies has been the failure to
interoperate with one another.  Cryptocurrency platforms are competing for
dominance with their own, largely incompatible technical roadmaps. It’s as if
each blockchain consensus system with its own community is too sovereign for
its own good.</p>
<p>Mechanisms like <a href="https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Atomic_cross-chain_trading">atomic swaps</a> between chains can
certainly help to link communities. However, where there are no technical
issues, they often suffer from a need for mature liquidity markets and active
participants on each side. Thus the “altcoin” ecosystem is an alchemical soup
of enthusiasts experimenting in various ways. Many possess new designs and
convictions, yet often each stands alone, siloed by the lack of a general
inter-blockchain communication system.</p>
<p>Ethereum sought to address this problem, somewhat indirectly, by inventing a
new platform for computation. Ethereum allows arbitrary financial systems to be
written against a common virtual machine using a common development
environment. Presuming all new cryptocurrencies launch on Ethereum, they will
have some capacity for interoperability.</p>
<p>Ethereum is in fact a wonderful idea. Its design decisions are motivated by
important considerations such as the need for a simple specification and
guaranteed determinism. However, it neglects elements such as the difficulty of
designing a secure general purpose programming environment. This means Ethereum
has its own sovereignty problem, as it excludes developers who want access to
the platform but want alternatives to the current <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finite-state_machine">state transition machine</a>.</p>
<p>Ethereum also doesn’t address the problem of turning fiat currency into
fungible tokens, short of having banks and government bodies issue currency on
Ethereum itself. While many institutions are investigating the Ethereum
blockchain, there are both scalability and governance concerns which ultimately
restrict full-scale adoption. This may impede integration with existing systems
and currencies.</p>
<p>Much like communities, companies and nation-states, each existing
cryptocurrency is born with the seed of some cultural ideal. Bitcoin is
decidedly libertarian, with a slight anarchist leaning. Ethereum is less a
political statement and more an avant-garde academic exercise in distributed
systems, computer science and contract theory. Dogecoin is a testament to the
capacity for humans to bond over the absurd, a phenomenon more commonly known
as “being social”. Steem offers a more structured version of this same
behavior, with a basis in content production and curation.</p>
<p>And so on, down the line. But there are many more viewpoints in the world, each
doubtlessly wanting a unique experiment in the intersection between governance,
culture and economics. It would be a tragedy for all these experiments to be so
rigidly siloed from one another by great chasms of incompatibility.</p>
<p>Clearly, what is needed is something that can integrate the states of existing
blockchains. Something that can interface in a sane manner with everything from
novelty rewards points to currencies issued by nation-states. Something for
formalizing relationships between systems, without compromising independence.
Something with extreme flexibility without compromising security.</p>
<p>Enter Cosmos, the “Internet of Blockchains”. Cosmos is a network and a
framework for interoperability between blockchains. It consists of a web of
hubs and zones, where each zone is effectively an independent blockchain with
an arbitrary cryptocurrency design (such as Bitcoin, Ethereum, ZeroCash,
CryptoNote, your local banking institution, etc.). Each hub is a multi-asset
cryptocurrency that facilitates interoperability between some set of zones.</p>
<p>Hubs and zones are powered by the Tendermint Proof-of-Stake (TMSP) consensus
algorithm, using the TMSP interface to host applications written in any
programming language. TMSP permits enormous flexibility in application design
and enables the application to inherit the security features of a
Tendermint-powered blockchain. In fact, Cosmos is compatible with any Byzantine
Fault Tolerant system, which is the basis of Tendermint itself.</p>
<p>Zones communicate with one another through a hub, primarily in the form of
asymmetric transfer of some set of tokens from one zone to another.
Effectively, a hub is a blockchain with many sidechains, but using PoS instead
of PoW leads to a dramatic reduction in overhead without sacrificing security.
Each zone acts as a light client for the hub, and the hub acts as a light
client for all its zones. Tendermint makes this efficient with compact light
client proofs that are secure so long as the validator set is known. This can
be achieved by ensuring the light client synchronizes with validator set
changes at least as often as they are permitted to occur.</p>
<p>Cosmos makes no distinction between hubs. There is no top hub and the most
popular or successful hub is a matter of adoption by zones. Furthermore, there
is no fundamental distinction between zones and hubs, such that any zone with
sufficient functionality can become a hub. Cosmos will release one particular
hub in order to get things started, the aptly named Adam hub. There is nothing
stopping this hub from becoming obsolete, or stopping the likes of Bitcoin or
Ethereum from competing with it and potentially replacing it.</p>
<p>Cosmos thus introduces a new kind of market dynamic that formalizes the
friction points between various cryptocurrency offerings. It demolishes
barriers to interoperability by enabling competition between hubs to contribute
to the economic security of each hub itself. Validators who misbehave will be
abandoned for better behaving ones. The result is a heterogeneous network – an
Internet of Blockchains – adapting for each community and each locale
according to its needs, all while retaining a backbone of interoperability. The
goal is keeping barriers to entry low while holding stewards of the system
accountable.</p>
<p>Cosmos’ potential is building synergy and unlocking the power that exists in
every cryptocurrency. As operators in one particular echo chamber of consensus
systems design, Cosmos believes interoperability is the key to unlocking the
collective developments of this industry. With the Internet of Blockchains,
companies and individuals can utilize the services of one chain, without
abandoning their existing investments in another. This creates a world that is
fairer, more functional and better secured. This is a call for an end to echo
chambers, and the beginning of bridge-building.</p>
]]></description><link>http://cosmos.network/posts/purpose-of-cosmos</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://cosmos.network/posts/purpose-of-cosmos</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jae Kwon & Ethan Buchman]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[BFT: The Most Secure Proof-of-Stake]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin brought the world’s attention to the blockchain. But alas, the Bitcoin
version of blockchain isn’t sufficient for the world’s blockchain needs. That
is because Bitcoin’s proof of work (PoW) consensus <a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/read/bitcoin-could-consume-as-much-electricity-as-denmark-by-2020">requires an enormous amounts
of energy</a>. In addition, transactions are painstakingly slow, taking an hour or
longer to commit. And because PoW miners have little incentive to be loyal to
one chain or other, upgrades are difficult to coordinate.</p>
<p>We need an approach to manage blockchains securely that does not impose a huge
energy cost on our planet. That approach is Byzantine fault-tolerance
(BFT)-based <a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=27787.0">proof-of-stake</a> (PoS).  We call it BFT-PoS.</p>
<p>Before I delve into the merits of BFT-PoS, let me first address the concept of
Byzantine faults without going into confusing detail about <a href="http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~sschang/OS-Qual/reliability/byzantine.htm">Lamport’s General
and his armies</a>.</p>
<p>In a distributed system, where data is replicated across hundreds or thousands
of nodes, there needs to be some type of fault-tolerance or consensus
algorithm, for the simple fact that computers break down or go offline from
time to time. So if a portion of those nodes fail, the system as a whole still
needs to reach a consensus.</p>
<p>Standard fault-tolerant consensus algorithms like
<a href="https://raft.github.io/raft.pdf">Raft</a> and
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paxos_(computer_science)">Paxos</a> assume that
when a node fails, it simply stops working and doesn’t send back a reply.
Google, Facebook, and some existing database products already use this family
of consensus algorithms within their firewalls to ensure that services remain
available despite faulty computers.</p>
<p>But these algorithms aren’t suitable for public blockchains, because there is
no firewall in a public blockchain.  Anyone with mining power (in PoW) or
staking tokens (in PoS) can participate, or even try to sabotage the network.
To reach consensus on a public blockchain, we need Byzantine fault-tolerance.
In a Byzantine fault, the faulty node can behave in a completely arbitrary
manner. Nodes can even collude to try and maximize the damage they cause.</p>
<p>So essentially, the purpose of a BFT consensus algorithm is to establish trust
between otherwise unrelated parties over an untrusted network like the
Internet.</p>
<p>BFT is nothing new. The concept was first introduced in an academic paper by
<a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/people/lamport/pubs/byz.pdf">Lamport, Shostak, and Pease in
1982</a>. But
Lamport et al only demonstrated the theoretical feasibility of the algorithm in
a synchronous environment, where all the messages always arrive on time.</p>
<p>But in the real world, you can’t really trust the Internet to deliver anything
on time. So in 1988, <a href="http://groups.csail.mit.edu/tds/papers/Lynch/jacm88.pdf">Dwork, Lynch, and Stockmeyer</a> (DLS) proposed an algorithm
that works in mostly asynchronous environments.  Later in 1999, <a href="http://pmg.csail.mit.edu/papers/osdi99.pdf">Miguel Castro
and Barbara Liskov</a> proposed a practical solution for continuous BFT consensus
that was, and still is today, the state-of-the-art in BFT algorithms.</p>
<p>But for a long time, the mainstream press ignored these seminal works. Nobody
understood the importance of BFT outside academia and major institutions like
IBM and DARPA, until 2009 when Bitcoin came along. Bitcoin was the first open
decentralized application to provide BFT consensus on a global currency ledger,
but using a completely novel solution to the Byzantine general’s problem: PoW.</p>
<p>In PoW, miners compete, based on who has the most processing power, to validate
transactions. And for their efforts they are rewarded with transaction fees and
newly minted bitcoins. This is how Bitcoin creates new currency.  Bitcoin
miners around the globe compete in a lottery-like system for these newly issued
bitcoins, and the efficient market makes it so that the cost of the energy used
by the global mining network is on the order of the block reward (plus
transaction fees).  Today, that turns out to be around $1M worth of electricity
per day.  In addition, Bitcoin mining is being commoditized by <a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=1072474.0">large data
centers in places of the world where electricity is more affordable</a>, making it
difficult for laymen to participate.</p>
<p>PoS, on the other hand, does away with the energy dependence of PoW entirely.
In PoS, miners are replaced with “validators” who have a stake in the system.
Validators don’t have to invest in expensive processing systems but they do
have to purchase “staking tokens.” Any normal laptop will suffice to solve the
algorithm.</p>
<p>Peercoin, <a href="https://bitshares.org/">BitShares</a>,
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nxt">Nxt</a>, and others already use some form of
PoS, and Ethereum is planning a move to PoS in the near future. Yet, while PoS
makes practical sense, many people have <a href="https://download.wpsoftware.net/bitcoin/pos.pdf">rallied against the use of
PoS</a>, claiming it is
impossible to secure. But that is simply not true. Using BFT, you absolutely
can secure PoS.  It’s just that we haven’t seen any BFT-PoS public blockchains
yet.</p>
<p>While the theory may be difficult to explain or understand, the ultimate
results provided by proper BFT algorithms are simple to grasp.  Unlike PoW
blockchains, BFT-PoS blockchains do not fork (i.e. get double-spend attacked)
at all unless ⅓ or more validators coordinate such an attack.  And, when 1/3 or
more validators do cause a double-spend attack, we can computationally
determine which validators were responsible for the attack, destroy their
staking tokens and eject them from the network.  It’s as if the staking tokens
are virtualized PoW miners that blow up when used to attack the system.  No
other blockchain consensus algorithm, including PoW, can provide the level of
collateralization that is possible with BFT-PoS.</p>
<p>BFT-PoS performs extremely well. Today, in global public blockchain with a few
hundred validators, you can get transaction finality on the  order of 3
seconds, easily – no need to wait for additional block confirmations! The
theory has proven to us that these are optimal fault-tolerance thresholds for
“instant-finality” blockchains.  While more validators does slow down
consensus, if <a href="https://www.nngroup.com/articles/law-of-bandwidth/">Nielsen’s
law</a> continues to hold,
we’ll even be able to support an exponentially increasing number of validators
every year with the same performance.</p>
<p>In addition, BFT-PoS will also increase the security of mobile wallets. Few of
the mobile wallets in existence today take full advantage of the security
offered by Bitcoin, for the simple fact that nobody is willing to wait an hour
for a transaction to clear. Instead, most wallets just assume that <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/buzz/peter-todd-explains-the-problems-with-unconfirmed-bitcoin-transactions">the person
sending the money isn’t trying to double spend
it</a>.
And, though we don’t have time to dive into it here, efficient mobile wallet
protocols, or “light client SPV” protocols are the key to future blockchain
interoperability.</p>
<p>While PoW worked well for Bitcoin, it’s costly, slow, and environmentally
unfriendly. The best alternative out there right now is BFT-PoS. It’s an
enduring, energy efficient solution that works well in asynchronous
environments. And best of all, because BFT was developed by the best and the
brightest in the computer science industry, it’s provably secure. You can’t do
any better than that.</p>
]]></description><link>http://cosmos.network/posts/bft-the-most-secure-proof-of-stake</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://cosmos.network/posts/bft-the-most-secure-proof-of-stake</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jae Kwon]]></dc:creator></item></channel></rss>