<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Cosmos Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Internet of Blockchains]]></description><link>http://cosmos.network</link><image><url>http://cosmos.network/static/favicon.png</url><title>Cosmos Blog</title><link>http://cosmos.network</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 05:49:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cosmos.network/static//rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 05:49:37 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[2016 Cosmos Foundation]]></copyright><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><managingEditor><![CDATA[Cosmos Foundation]]></managingEditor><webMaster><![CDATA[Cosmos Foundation]]></webMaster><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Why We Are Building the Internet of Blockchains]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>One of the great tragedies of cryptocurrencies has been the failure to
interoperate with one another.  Cryptocurrency platforms are competing for
dominance with their own, largely incompatible technical roadmaps. It’s as if
each blockchain consensus system with its own community is too sovereign for
its own good.</p>
<p>Mechanisms like <a href="https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Atomic_cross-chain_trading">atomic swaps</a> between chains can
certainly help to link communities. However, where there are no technical
issues, they often suffer from a need for mature liquidity markets and active
participants on each side. Thus the “altcoin” ecosystem is an alchemical soup
of enthusiasts experimenting in various ways. Many possess new designs and
convictions, yet often each stands alone, siloed by the lack of a general
inter-blockchain communication system.</p>
<p>Ethereum sought to address this problem, somewhat indirectly, by inventing a
new platform for computation. Ethereum allows arbitrary financial systems to be
written against a common virtual machine using a common development
environment. Presuming all new cryptocurrencies launch on Ethereum, they will
have some capacity for interoperability.</p>
<p>Ethereum is in fact a wonderful idea. Its design decisions are motivated by
important considerations such as the need for a simple specification and
guaranteed determinism. However, it neglects elements such as the difficulty of
designing a secure general purpose programming environment. This means Ethereum
has its own sovereignty problem, as it excludes developers who want access to
the platform but want alternatives to the current <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finite-state_machine">state transition machine</a>.</p>
<p>Ethereum also doesn’t address the problem of turning fiat currency into
fungible tokens, short of having banks and government bodies issue currency on
Ethereum itself. While many institutions are investigating the Ethereum
blockchain, there are both scalability and governance concerns which ultimately
restrict full-scale adoption. This may impede integration with existing systems
and currencies.</p>
<p>Much like communities, companies and nation-states, each existing
cryptocurrency is born with the seed of some cultural ideal. Bitcoin is
decidedly libertarian, with a slight anarchist leaning. Ethereum is less a
political statement and more an avant-garde academic exercise in distributed
systems, computer science and contract theory. Dogecoin is a testament to the
capacity for humans to bond over the absurd, a phenomenon more commonly known
as “being social”. Steem offers a more structured version of this same
behavior, with a basis in content production and curation.</p>
<p>And so on, down the line. But there are many more viewpoints in the world, each
doubtlessly wanting a unique experiment in the intersection between governance,
culture and economics. It would be a tragedy for all these experiments to be so
rigidly siloed from one another by great chasms of incompatibility.</p>
<p>Clearly, what is needed is something that can integrate the states of existing
blockchains. Something that can interface in a sane manner with everything from
novelty rewards points to currencies issued by nation-states. Something for
formalizing relationships between systems, without compromising independence.
Something with extreme flexibility without compromising security.</p>
<p>Enter Cosmos, the “Internet of Blockchains”. Cosmos is a network and a
framework for interoperability between blockchains. It consists of a web of
hubs and zones, where each zone is effectively an independent blockchain with
an arbitrary cryptocurrency design (such as Bitcoin, Ethereum, ZeroCash,
CryptoNote, your local banking institution, etc.). Each hub is a multi-asset
cryptocurrency that facilitates interoperability between some set of zones.</p>
<p>Hubs and zones are powered by the Tendermint Proof-of-Stake (TMSP) consensus
algorithm, using the TMSP interface to host applications written in any
programming language. TMSP permits enormous flexibility in application design
and enables the application to inherit the security features of a
Tendermint-powered blockchain. In fact, Cosmos is compatible with any Byzantine
Fault Tolerant system, which is the basis of Tendermint itself.</p>
<p>Zones communicate with one another through a hub, primarily in the form of
asymmetric transfer of some set of tokens from one zone to another.
Effectively, a hub is a blockchain with many sidechains, but using PoS instead
of PoW leads to a dramatic reduction in overhead without sacrificing security.
Each zone acts as a light client for the hub, and the hub acts as a light
client for all its zones. Tendermint makes this efficient with compact light
client proofs that are secure so long as the validator set is known. This can
be achieved by ensuring the light client synchronizes with validator set
changes at least as often as they are permitted to occur.</p>
<p>Cosmos makes no distinction between hubs. There is no top hub and the most
popular or successful hub is a matter of adoption by zones. Furthermore, there
is no fundamental distinction between zones and hubs, such that any zone with
sufficient functionality can become a hub. Cosmos will release one particular
hub in order to get things started, the aptly named Adam hub. There is nothing
stopping this hub from becoming obsolete, or stopping the likes of Bitcoin or
Ethereum from competing with it and potentially replacing it.</p>
<p>Cosmos thus introduces a new kind of market dynamic that formalizes the
friction points between various cryptocurrency offerings. It demolishes
barriers to interoperability by enabling competition between hubs to contribute
to the economic security of each hub itself. Validators who misbehave will be
abandoned for better behaving ones. The result is a heterogeneous network – an
Internet of Blockchains – adapting for each community and each locale
according to its needs, all while retaining a backbone of interoperability. The
goal is keeping barriers to entry low while holding stewards of the system
accountable.</p>
<p>Cosmos’ potential is building synergy and unlocking the power that exists in
every cryptocurrency. As operators in one particular echo chamber of consensus
systems design, Cosmos believes interoperability is the key to unlocking the
collective developments of this industry. With the Internet of Blockchains,
companies and individuals can utilize the services of one chain, without
abandoning their existing investments in another. This creates a world that is
fairer, more functional and better secured. This is a call for an end to echo
chambers, and the beginning of bridge-building.</p>
]]></description><link>http://cosmos.network/posts/purpose-of-cosmos</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://cosmos.network/posts/purpose-of-cosmos</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jae Kwon & Ethan Buchman]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[BFT: The Most Secure Proof-of-Stake]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin brought the world’s attention to the blockchain. But alas, the Bitcoin
version of blockchain isn’t sufficient for the world’s blockchain needs. That
is because Bitcoin’s proof of work (PoW) consensus <a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/read/bitcoin-could-consume-as-much-electricity-as-denmark-by-2020">requires an enormous amounts
of energy</a>. In addition, transactions are painstakingly slow, taking an hour or
longer to commit. And because PoW miners have little incentive to be loyal to
one chain or other, upgrades are difficult to coordinate.</p>
<p>We need an approach to manage blockchains securely that does not impose a huge
energy cost on our planet. That approach is Byzantine fault-tolerance
(BFT)-based <a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=27787.0">proof-of-stake</a> (PoS).  We call it BFT-PoS.</p>
<p>Before I delve into the merits of BFT-PoS, let me first address the concept of
Byzantine faults without going into confusing detail about <a href="http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~sschang/OS-Qual/reliability/byzantine.htm">Lamport’s General
and his armies</a>.</p>
<p>In a distributed system, where data is replicated across hundreds or thousands
of nodes, there needs to be some type of fault-tolerance or consensus
algorithm, for the simple fact that computers break down or go offline from
time to time. So if a portion of those nodes fail, the system as a whole still
needs to reach a consensus.</p>
<p>Standard fault-tolerant consensus algorithms like
<a href="https://raft.github.io/raft.pdf">Raft</a> and
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paxos_(computer_science)">Paxos</a> assume that
when a node fails, it simply stops working and doesn’t send back a reply.
Google, Facebook, and some existing database products already use this family
of consensus algorithms within their firewalls to ensure that services remain
available despite faulty computers.</p>
<p>But these algorithms aren’t suitable for public blockchains, because there is
no firewall in a public blockchain.  Anyone with mining power (in PoW) or
staking tokens (in PoS) can participate, or even try to sabotage the network.
To reach consensus on a public blockchain, we need Byzantine fault-tolerance.
In a Byzantine fault, the faulty node can behave in a completely arbitrary
manner. Nodes can even collude to try and maximize the damage they cause.</p>
<p>So essentially, the purpose of a BFT consensus algorithm is to establish trust
between otherwise unrelated parties over an untrusted network like the
Internet.</p>
<p>BFT is nothing new. The concept was first introduced in an academic paper by
<a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/people/lamport/pubs/byz.pdf">Lamport, Shostak, and Pease in
1982</a>. But
Lamport et al only demonstrated the theoretical feasibility of the algorithm in
a synchronous environment, where all the messages always arrive on time.</p>
<p>But in the real world, you can’t really trust the Internet to deliver anything
on time. So in 1988, <a href="http://groups.csail.mit.edu/tds/papers/Lynch/jacm88.pdf">Dwork, Lynch, and Stockmeyer</a> (DLS) proposed an algorithm
that works in mostly asynchronous environments.  Later in 1999, <a href="http://pmg.csail.mit.edu/papers/osdi99.pdf">Miguel Castro
and Barbara Liskov</a> proposed a practical solution for continuous BFT consensus
that was, and still is today, the state-of-the-art in BFT algorithms.</p>
<p>But for a long time, the mainstream press ignored these seminal works. Nobody
understood the importance of BFT outside academia and major institutions like
IBM and DARPA, until 2009 when Bitcoin came along. Bitcoin was the first open
decentralized application to provide BFT consensus on a global currency ledger,
but using a completely novel solution to the Byzantine general’s problem: PoW.</p>
<p>In PoW, miners compete, based on who has the most processing power, to validate
transactions. And for their efforts they are rewarded with transaction fees and
newly minted bitcoins. This is how Bitcoin creates new currency.  Bitcoin
miners around the globe compete in a lottery-like system for these newly issued
bitcoins, and the efficient market makes it so that the cost of the energy used
by the global mining network is on the order of the block reward (plus
transaction fees).  Today, that turns out to be around $1M worth of electricity
per day.  In addition, Bitcoin mining is being commoditized by <a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=1072474.0">large data
centers in places of the world where electricity is more affordable</a>, making it
difficult for laymen to participate.</p>
<p>PoS, on the other hand, does away with the energy dependence of PoW entirely.
In PoS, miners are replaced with “validators” who have a stake in the system.
Validators don’t have to invest in expensive processing systems but they do
have to purchase “staking tokens.” Any normal laptop will suffice to solve the
algorithm.</p>
<p>Peercoin, <a href="https://bitshares.org/">BitShares</a>,
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nxt">Nxt</a>, and others already use some form of
PoS, and Ethereum is planning a move to PoS in the near future. Yet, while PoS
makes practical sense, many people have <a href="https://download.wpsoftware.net/bitcoin/pos.pdf">rallied against the use of
PoS</a>, claiming it is
impossible to secure. But that is simply not true. Using BFT, you absolutely
can secure PoS.  It’s just that we haven’t seen any BFT-PoS public blockchains
yet.</p>
<p>While the theory may be difficult to explain or understand, the ultimate
results provided by proper BFT algorithms are simple to grasp.  Unlike PoW
blockchains, BFT-PoS blockchains do not fork (i.e. get double-spend attacked)
at all unless ⅓ or more validators coordinate such an attack.  And, when 1/3 or
more validators do cause a double-spend attack, we can computationally
determine which validators were responsible for the attack, destroy their
staking tokens and eject them from the network.  It’s as if the staking tokens
are virtualized PoW miners that blow up when used to attack the system.  No
other blockchain consensus algorithm, including PoW, can provide the level of
collateralization that is possible with BFT-PoS.</p>
<p>BFT-PoS performs extremely well. Today, in global public blockchain with a few
hundred validators, you can get transaction finality on the  order of 3
seconds, easily – no need to wait for additional block confirmations! The
theory has proven to us that these are optimal fault-tolerance thresholds for
“instant-finality” blockchains.  While more validators does slow down
consensus, if <a href="https://www.nngroup.com/articles/law-of-bandwidth/">Nielsen’s
law</a> continues to hold,
we’ll even be able to support an exponentially increasing number of validators
every year with the same performance.</p>
<p>In addition, BFT-PoS will also increase the security of mobile wallets. Few of
the mobile wallets in existence today take full advantage of the security
offered by Bitcoin, for the simple fact that nobody is willing to wait an hour
for a transaction to clear. Instead, most wallets just assume that <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/buzz/peter-todd-explains-the-problems-with-unconfirmed-bitcoin-transactions">the person
sending the money isn’t trying to double spend
it</a>.
And, though we don’t have time to dive into it here, efficient mobile wallet
protocols, or “light client SPV” protocols are the key to future blockchain
interoperability.</p>
<p>While PoW worked well for Bitcoin, it’s costly, slow, and environmentally
unfriendly. The best alternative out there right now is BFT-PoS. It’s an
enduring, energy efficient solution that works well in asynchronous
environments. And best of all, because BFT was developed by the best and the
brightest in the computer science industry, it’s provably secure. You can’t do
any better than that.</p>
]]></description><link>http://cosmos.network/posts/bft-the-most-secure-proof-of-stake</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://cosmos.network/posts/bft-the-most-secure-proof-of-stake</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jae Kwon]]></dc:creator></item></channel></rss>